Guide to the Edgar Hockley Collection
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Designs by Production, Series II; Hockley, Edgar, 1860-1938
  - The Three Musketeers: drawings of a male with a hat on his knee, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 12 x 20 cm (Box 2, Folder 21.1a)
    Includes the note "The Three Musketeers."
  - The Three Musketeers: drawing of a male with his right hand on his hip, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 21.1b)
    Includes detail and color notes on the hat, feather, tunic, necklace, sword, satchel, breeches, hose, shoes, cloak, etc.
  - The Three Musketeers: drawings of Porthos, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 21.1c)
    Includes detail and color notes on the hair, tunic, belt, cloak, sash, trousers, boots, etc.
  - The Three Musketeers: drawings of Cardinal Richelieu and various males, circa 1886-1897; 4 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 21.1d)
    Includes detail and color notes on Richelieu's clerical costume, as well as various poses and notes concerning a male character in a cloak.
  - The Three Musketeers: drawing of Cardinal Richelieu and a kneeling female, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 21.1e)
    Graphite drawings; Dumas, Alexandre, 1802-1870. Trois mousquetaires. English; Costume design drawings
  - The Three Musketeers: drawings of the Cardinal, the Cardinal on a settee, and a female, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 21.1(f))
    Includes detail and color notes for the Cardinal's dress and cloak, the room with a settee, etc.
    Graphite drawings; Set design drawings; Costume design drawings; Dumas, Alexandre, 1802-1870. Trois mousquetaires. English
  - The Three Musketeers: drawings of the Cardinal and a female kneeling before him, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 21.1g)
    Includes detail and color notes for the Cardinal's cloak, toga, as well as a dress for "Milady." The faint beginnings of two drawings of the Cardinal appear on the verso.
  - Twelfth Night: drawings and descriptions of costumes for major characters, circa 1886-1897; 14 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 45.5 x 28.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 22a)
    Contains extensive detail and color notes on costumes for Viola, a Sea Captain, two sailors, Sir Andrew, Olivia, Maria, Fabian, Antonio, Malvolio, and Sir Toby Belch. The drawings are all smaller than 6.5 x 6 cm.
    Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Twelfth night
- Designs by Era, Series III; Hockley, Edgar, 1860-1938
  - Greco/Roman (female): drawing of a female wearing a wreath, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 13 x 10 cm (Box 3, Folder 1a)
    Includes detail and color notes for the dress, cloak, and wreath.
    Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings
  - Greco/Roman (female): drawings of female in action, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 1b)
    Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings
  - Greco/Roman (female): drawing of a female with a jewel on her head, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 9.5 x 5 cm (Box 3, Folder 1c)
    Includes detail and color notes for the jewel and dress.
  - Greco/Roman (female): drawings of a female in various poses, circa 1886-1897; 7 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 1(d))
    Includes notes on the bag, the dagger, and the sandal.
  - Greco/Roman (female): drawings of a female in a cloak, circa 1886-1897; 5 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 12 x 19 cm (Box 3, Folder 1e)
  - Greco/Roman (male): drawing of a male before another male on a throne, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 8.5 x 17 cm (Box 3, Folder 2a)
  - Greco/Roman (male): drawing of a male with arms crossed, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: pen and ink and watercolor; 13.5 x 8 cm (Box 3, Folder 2b)
    Reverse is signed "G. Harrison, Esq" in graphite.
    Watercolors; Costume design drawings; Pen and ink drawings
  - Greco/Roman (male): drawing of a male holding a sword near cliffs, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 20 x 13 cm (Box 3, Folder 2c)
    Includes detail and color notes for the cloak, tunic, hose, cliffs, etc. Reserve side of sheet features the faint beginning of another drawing.
    Set design drawings; Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings
  - Greco/Roman (male): drawing of a male, front view, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 7 x 3 cm (Box 3, Folder 2(d))
    Drawing made on blue paper.
  - Greco/Roman (male): drawings of a male in two positions, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 12 x 19 cm (Box 3, Folder 2e)
    Includes detail and color notes for the cape.
  - Greco/Roman (male): drawing of a male draped in cloak, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 12 x 19 cm (Box 3, Folder 2(f))
    Includes detail and color notes for the cloak.
  - Greco/Roman (male & female): drawings of a male as well as a male embracing a female, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 12.5 x 10.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 3a)
  - Greco/Roman (male & female): drawings of a male embracing a female and a male and a female in nature, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 20 x 13 cm (Box 3, Folder 3b)
    First drawing depicts a male and a female embracing in front of a throne. Second drawing depicts a male with a spear facing a female, with hunters on either side.
  - Greco/Roman (male & female): drawing of a male handing a document to a female on a chair, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 20 x 13 cm (Box 3, Folder 3c)
    Includes color and detail notes for the dress, necklace, cloak, chair, tunic, shields, etc.
    Costume design drawings; Set design drawings; Graphite drawings
  - Greco/Roman (male & female): drawings of a male and a female with spears, circa 1886-1897; 15 drawings on 1 sheet (two sides): graphite; 20 x 13 cm (Box 3, Folder 3(d))
    The recto features 12 drawings; the verso features 3 drawings.
  - Greco/Roman (male & female): drawings of a male holding a female aloft, a winged female, and a female with a cloak, circa 1886-1897; 5 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 16 x 10.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 3e)
    Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings; Set design drawings
  - Medieval (female): drawing of a female in blue, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor over graphite; 20 x 13 cm (Box 3, Folder 4a)
    Sheet is torn (in three places, approx. 1.5 cm each) and wrinkled in lower left corner.
    Graphite drawings; Set design drawings; Costume design drawings; Watercolors
  - Medieval (female): drawing of a female in a dress and a cloak, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 17.5 x 11 cm (Box 3, Folder 4b)
    Includes detail and color notes for the hair, medals, dress, cloak, etc.
  - Medieval (female): drawing of a female in a gown and a crown, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 12 cm (Box 3, Folder 4c)
  - Medieval (male): drawings of a male and his costume detail, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 20 x 13 cm (Box 3, Folder 5a)
    Includes detail and color notes for the chain, rings, tunic, fur, garter, hose, shoes, satchel, etc.
  - Medieval (male): drawing of a male with a mustache, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 3, Folder 5b)
    Includes detail and color notes for the hair, cloak, sword, belt, sleeves, etc.
  - Medieval (male): drawings of males in church, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 3, Folder 5c)
    Includes detail and color notes for the costumes. Reverse side of the sheet has "grand" written in graphite.
  - Medieval (male): drawing of a male in a dark room, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 19 x 12 cm (Box 3, Folder 5(d))
    Includes detail and color notes for the costumes, wall, curtains, floor, etc.
  - Medieval (male): drawings of a male in royal garb and males in nature, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings: graphite; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 5e)
    Includes detail and color notes for the cap, hair, tunic, hose, etc.
    Set design drawings; Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings
  - Medieval (male): drawings of males in various costumes, circa 1886-1897; 7 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 13 x 21 cm (Box 3, Folder 5(f))
    Includes detail and color notes for the costumes and the "moustache of king."
  - Medieval (male): drawings of three males, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 5g)
    Includes detail and color notes for the tunics, cloaks, hair, hose, etc.
  - Medieval (male): drawing of a male with a medal necklace, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 3, Folder 5h)
    Includes detail and color notes for the tunic, medals, sleeves, cloak, boots, etc.
  - Medieval (male): drawing of a male looking downward, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 3, Folder 5.1a)
    Reverse side of the sheet has "grand" written in graphite.
  - Medieval (male): drawings of three males with fabric detail, circa 1886-1897; 4 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 13 x 21 cm (Box 3, Folder 5.1b)
    Includes detail and number-coded color notes for hair, tunics, cloaks, boots, etc.
  - Medieval (male): drawing of a male with a crown and a chair, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 3, Folder 5.1c)
  - Medieval (male): drawing of a male with his right hand on his hip, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor over graphite; 13 x 10.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 5.1d)
    The watercolor (8 x 5 cm) is affixed to the larger sheet, which includes detail and color notes for the hose, tunic, cloak, etc.
    Watercolors; Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings
  - Medieval (male): drawing of a male with a dagger on his belt, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: gouache and watercolor over graphite; 20 x 13 cm (Box 3, Folder 5.1e)
    Watercolors; Graphite drawings; Gouaches; Costume design drawings
  - Medieval (male): drawings of males with close-up costume detail, circa 1886-1897; 7 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 5.1(f))
    Includes detail and color notes for the hose, cloaks, tunics, swords, a satchel, a helmet, hair, etc.
  - Medieval (male): drawings of a male holding a scroll and a male in a cloak, circa 1886-1897; 8 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 20 x 13 cm (Box 3, Folder 5.1g)
    Includes brief detail and color notes for the cloak and gold chain.
  - Medieval (male & female): drawings of a male costume and a female figure, circa 1886-1897; 5 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 6a)
    Includes detail and color notes for the hat, hair, beard, tunic, hose, fur, dagger, etc. Writing identifies the female as "Celia," possibly connecting the drawing to Shakespeare's As You Like It.
    Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. As you like it
  - Medieval (male & female): drawings of females in various costumes, circa 1886-1897; 6 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 6b)
    Includes detail and color notes for the headdress, tunic, dress, underskirt, etc.
  - Medieval (male & female): drawings of a male in a tunic and a female holding a lute, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 6c)
    Includes detail and color notes for the tunic, dress, hair, etc. The sheet is creased halfway through from top to bottom.
  - Medieval (soldiers): drawings of males in armor and on horses, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 7a)
    Includes brief detail and color notes for one character's shoulder and trousers.
  - Medieval (soldiers): drawing of a march through a town, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 13 x 20 cm (Box 3, Folder 7b)
    Depicts shambles architecture.
  - Medieval (Crusades): drawings of soldiers on a hill and a Queen under a canopy, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 3, Folder 8a)
    Includes detail and color notes for the sky, costumes, Queen, canopy, etc.
    Graphite drawings; Set design drawings; Costume design drawings
  - Medieval (Crusades): drawings of three males and a female with a crown, circa 1886-1897; 4 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 3, Folder 8b)
    Includes detail and color notes for the hose, sword, crest, crown, etc.
  - Medieval (Crusades): drawing of a King, a Queen, and two others on a river bank, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 3, Folder 8c)
    Includes detail and color notes for the river bank, grass, trees, king, queen, dog daisies, cloud etc.
  - Medieval (Crusades): drawings of two females and a male in the woods and other figures, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: pen and ink; 18 x 11 cm (Box 3, Folder 8(d))
    "Chain" is written in lower right corner of the drawing. Researcher's notes indicate the drawing may depict a scene from Shakespeare's As You Like It or Cymbeline.
    Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. As you like it; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Cymbeline; Pen and ink drawings; Set design drawings
  - Medieval (Crusades): drawing of a plaza at Alhambra, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 8e)
    Includes detail and color notes for the walls, greenhouse, mountains, pillars, Alhambra, pergola, tiles, etc.
    Set design drawings; Graphite drawings
  - Medieval (Crusades): drawing of figures in repose under a pavilion dome, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 3, Folder 8(f))
    Includes detail and color notes for the sky, pavilion dome, tents, ground, French soldiers, spears, dancer, etc.
  - Medieval (Crusades): drawings of three males and a chair, circa 1886-1897; 4 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 8g)
    Includes detail and color notes for the armor, helmet, tunic, belt, beard, spurs, chair, etc.
  - Medieval (Crusades): drawing of five males with swords, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 8h)
    Includes detail and color notes for the castle, walls, tunics, etc.
    Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings; Set design drawings
  - Medieval (scene): drawing of figures descending steps, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 9a)
    Possibly depicts dock scene.
  - Medieval (scene): drawing of a male kneeling before a king on a throne, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 13 x 20 cm (Box 3, Folder 9b)
  - Medieval (scene): drawing of a female crouching before a male, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 9c)
  - Medieval (scene): drawing of a room with a fireplace, table, and curtain, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor over graphite; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 9(d))
    The watercolor (6 x 12.5 cm) is affixed to the larger sheet.
    Graphite drawings; Set design drawings; Watercolors
  - Elizabethan (female): drawing of a female in a dress, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 17 x 9.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 10a)
    The drawing is an unfinished sketch on paper with a cut-off watermark that partially reads "--inal" and "--ne Mill."
  - Elizabethan (female): drawing of a female in a dress holding a kerchief, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor over graphite; 17 x 9.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 10b)
    Includes brief color notes for the dress.
    Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings; Watercolors
  - Elizabethan (male): drawing of a male in a multi-colored costume with an Elizabethan collar, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor over graphite; 13.5 x 10 cm (Box 3, Folder 11a)
  - Elizabethan (male): drawing of a male wearing a feathered cap and spurs, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 9 cm (Box 3, Folder 11b)
  - Elizabethan (male & female): drawings of a male with a sword and two females in dresses, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 12a)
    Includes detail and color notes for hair, sleeves, chain, cap, tunic, boots, dresses, etc.
  - Cavalier/17th Century (female): drawings of two females in dresses, one on a river bank, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: pen and ink; 12 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 13a)
    Includes detail and color notes for hair, dresses, water, leaves, cloak, etc.
    Set design drawings; Pen and ink drawings; Costume design drawings
  - Cavalier/17th Century (female): drawing of a female with a staff, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: pen and ink; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 13b)
    The verso includes detail and color notes likely for another drawing. A "moustache" and "yew hedges" are mentioned, neither of which appear in the drawing.
    Set design drawings; Costume design drawings; Pen and ink drawings
  - Cavalier/17th Century (male): drawings of a King and another male, circa 1886-1897; 7 drawings on 1 sheet: pen and ink; 23 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 14a)
    Includes detail and color notes on tunics, boots, spurs, belts, hair, cloak, and a table and a chair. The sheet contains a fold across the middle separating the top and bottom sections.
    Costume design drawings; Set design drawings; Pen and ink drawings
  - Cavalier/17th Century (male): drawings of two males, one with a sword and one with a stick, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: pen and ink and graphite; 18 x 23 cm (Box 3, Folder 14b)
    Includes detail and color notes on hat, hair, collar, cloak, armor, belt, etc. The sheet contains a fold across the middle separating the right and left sections.
    Pen and ink drawings; Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings
  - Cavalier/17th Century (male): drawings of a male in armor and a male in a plumed hat, circa 1886-1897; 5 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 14c)
    Includes detail and color notes on the helmet, tunic, cloak, hose, boots, moustache, etc.
  - Cavalier/17th Century (male): drawings of queen's page and mustachioed male, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 14d)
    Includes detail and color notes on the hair, hat, tunic, knickers, boots, etc.
  - Cavalier/17th Century (male & female): drawing of a male with a sword conversing with a female, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 9 cm (Box 3, Folder 15a)
    Includes detail and color notes on the dress, knickers, sword, etc.
  - Cavalier/17th Century (male & female): drawing of two males with riding crops and a female, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 15b)
    Includes detail and color notes on the tunics, hose, boots, etc.
  - Cavalier/17th Century (scene): drawing of a crowd in a bedchamber, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 8.5 x 13 cm (Box 3, Folder 16a)
  - Georgian (female): drawing of a female wearing a blue dress, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor and gouache over graphite; 14.5 x 10 cm (Box 3, Folder 16.2a)
    Folded sheet includes multiple drawings on both sides. The drawings (8 x 5 cm, 5.5 x 4.5 cm, 8 x 4.5) are affixed to the larger sheet, which includes detail and color notes for the costumes.
    Costume design drawings; Watercolors; Graphite drawings; Gouaches
  - Georgian (male): drawing of a male in a waistcoat, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 3, Folder 17a)
    Includes detail and color notes for the coat, waistcoat, knickers, hose, etc. The verso features the faint beginnings of another drawing.
  - Georgian (male): drawings of two males with whips, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 17b)
    Includes detail and color notes for the hats, hair, waistcoats, boots, breeches, etc. The verso features notes on the set design.
  - Georgian (male): drawings of two males, one with a knife and another with a walking stick, approaching two other males, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: pen and ink; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 17c)
    Includes brief detail and color notes for the costumes.
  - Georgian (male): drawing of a rotund male in a wig, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 17d)
    Includes detail and color notes for the wig, collar, coat, buttons, handkerchief, shoes, etc.
  - Georgian (male): drawing of three males smoking pipes, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 17e)
    Includes detail and color notes for the suits, hose, buttons, leggings, mantelpiece, etc.
  - Georgian (male): drawing of a male leaning with right hand aloft, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor and gouache over graphite and ink; 17.5 x 12 cm (Box 3, Folder 17(f))
    The drawing (5.5 x 4 cm) is affixed to the larger sheet, which includes detail and color notes for the coat, hose, necktie, wig, etc.
    Pen and ink drawings; Watercolors; Gouaches; Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings
  - Georgian (male & female): drawings of dresses and male finery, circa 1886-1897; 10 drawings on 1 sheet (2 sides): graphite and watercolor; 17.5 x 22.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 18a)
    Includes extensive detail and color notes for the dresses, hats, collars, buttons, coats, etc.
    Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings; Watercolors
  - Georgian (male & female): drawings of a female near a fireplace and various males, circa 1886-1897; 5 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 18b)
    Includes detail and color notes for the hat, bodice, hair, skirt, hose, shoes, table, fireplace, chimney, armchair, and footmen costumes.
  - Georgian (male & female): drawings of a female in an apron and two males, circa 1886-1897; 4 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 18c)
    Includes detail and color notes for the hair, apron, shoes, shoes, handkerchief, etc. Notes mention "Johnson" and "Boswell," perhaps indicating that the play was about Samuel Johnson and James Boswell.
  - Georgian (male & female): drawings of two males and one female in costume, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: watercolor and gouache over graphite and ink; 18 x 22 cm (Box 3, Folder 18d)
    Pen and ink drawings; Graphite drawings; Watercolors; Gouaches; Costume design drawings
  - Regency (male): drawings of a lion and eight males amongst trees, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 19a)
    Includes detail and color notes for the trees and clouds. The note may also identify the males in the drawing as "Dutchmen," however the handwriting cannot be confirmed.
  - Regency (male): drawing of a male leaning on a staircase railing, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 9.5 x 11.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 19b)
  - Regency (male): drawings of a male in a yellow coat, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: watercolor over graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 3, Folder 19c)
    Includes detail and color notes for the coat, necktie, etc.
  - Regency (male): drawings of a male wearing a hat, circa 1886-1897; 7 drawings on 1 sheet: pen and ink; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 19d)
    Costume design drawings; Pen and ink drawings
  - Regency (male & female): drawings of a female in a hat and a male with a sword, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 3, Folder 20a)
    Includes detail and color notes for the hat, cloak, dress, hair, cap, trousers, etc.
  - Victorian (female): drawing of a female in dress, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 8.5 x 6 cm (Box 3, Folder 21a)
    Drawing appears on a scrap of paper mentioning "Thomas & Co., Loan and Financial" on one side, and information regarding a conference or religious service ("doxology") on the other side.
  - Victorian (female): drawing of a female in a dress, view from the knee up, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 13 x 7 cm (Box 3, Folder 21b)
    Drawing appears on the verso of an advertisement which states: "Guaranteed to be of very superior quality." The trade mark listed belongs to the Sphinx brand of tobacco.